<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://bakery.ar/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://bakery.ar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-09T21:57:50+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Bakery</title><subtitle>Recipes with love by Ami Reynoso</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Cinnamon rolls</title><link href="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/cinnamon-rolls/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cinnamon rolls" /><published>2020-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/cinnamon-rolls</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/cinnamon-rolls/">&lt;p&gt;I’d had this very intense cinnamon roll craving for a while until I decided to act on it while watching Hamilton one summer weekend. It was quite late in the afternoon and from what I knew, cinnamon rolls take a couple of hours to make. Because I was lazy &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; hungry, I searched for the quickest cinnamon roll recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cinnamon-rolls-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close-up of a cinnamon roll&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://therecipecritic.com/quick-45-minute-cinnamon-rolls/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this beautiful recipe&lt;/a&gt; by The Recipe Critic, and it turned out to be amazing! I only modified it slightly to make it more to my tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a big batch and had to freeze the rest in order to force myself not to eat them all in one sitting. They were that good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cinnamon-rolls-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Freshly baked cinnamon rolls&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dough&quot;&gt;Dough&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 3/4 cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tbsp sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 1/4 tsp instant yeast (1 package)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;zest of 1 orange or lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;filling&quot;&gt;Filling&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;60 g unsalted butter at room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tbsp cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;glaze&quot;&gt;Glaze&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup powdered sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-3 tbps milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the bowl of a standing mixer, mix the flour, sugar, salt, zest and yeast. Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a bowl apt for microwaving (I use a measuing jar), heat the water, milk and butter for 30-45 seconds in the microwave, 1ntil the butter is melted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the liquid mixture into the bowl of the standing mixer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the egg (I always crack the egg in a ramekin first).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knead in medium speed for 3-4 minutes until the dough is no longer sticky.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the bowl aside and cover it with a damp towel. Let rest for at least 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 200ºF.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix the softened butter with the sugar and the cinnamon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After the dough has rested, roll it out to a big rectangle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread the butter mixture evenly on top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roll up the dough tightly. Cut into 8-9 even pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn off the oven.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the rolls in a lightly greased pan (I used a pie plate). Cover with plastic wrap.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the pan in the turned off oven for about 20 minutes, so rolls can rise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After 20 minutes, or when rolls have doubled in size, remove pan from the oven and remove the plastic wrap.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn on the oven to 375ºF. Wait until oven has reached this temperature before putting the pan back in the oven.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake cinnamon rolls for 15-20 minutes, until golden.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While rolls bake, make the glaze by mixing the powdered sugar, vanilla extract and milk until smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the pan from the oven and top rolls with glaze. Cool before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="cinnamon" /><category term="rolls" /><summary type="html">I’d had this very intense cinnamon roll craving for a while until I decided to act on it while watching Hamilton one summer weekend. It was quite late in the afternoon and from what I knew, cinnamon rolls take a couple of hours to make. Because I was lazy and hungry, I searched for the quickest cinnamon roll recipe.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/cinnamon-rolls.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/cinnamon-rolls.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Medialunas</title><link href="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/savoury/medialunas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Medialunas" /><published>2020-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/savoury/medialunas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/savoury/medialunas/">&lt;p&gt;If you go to any bakery in Argentina (in Buenos Aires you’ll see one every two blocks), you’ll find lots of &lt;em&gt;medialunas&lt;/em&gt;. They’re very similar to &lt;em&gt;croissants&lt;/em&gt; in shape but the texture is slightly different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many types of medialunas: butter-style, lard-style, filled with dulce de leche, filled with ham and cheese. They’re a very versatile type of pastry so they pair well with pretty much everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also find the name &lt;em&gt;medialuna&lt;/em&gt; magical. It means half-moon, and it obviously refers to its shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/medialunas-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Medialunas right out of the oven&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t had medialunas since I moved to Canada, and for some reason, there was a week where all Instagram showed me was recipes of medialunas. It was a sign (&lt;em&gt;that I share too much information with Facebook maybe&lt;/em&gt;). I had never made them before so I ventured to try it. I knew they usually take a long time to make, so I obviously looked for the quickest recipe. I chose &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/tv/CB6QN4Jlds5/?igshid=1w5e7lqgbaatb&quot;&gt;this recipe&lt;/a&gt; by Andrea Amatte on Instagram and they turned out beautiful and delicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/medialunas-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Single medialuna&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recipe makes a huge batch (I think around 30, depending on the size). I froze most of them, so they’re super convenient anytime, especially for breakfast. Seb loves them with ham and cheese (like a sandwich)! Just take them out of the freezer, warm them for 45 seconds on the microwave, fill them with whatever you want and bake for 5 minutes in a 300°F oven. Voilà!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dough&quot;&gt;Dough&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15g quick rise yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;500g all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;130g room-temperature butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;120g sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg (for egg wash)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;syrup&quot;&gt;Syrup&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 slices of any citrus fruit (i.e. lemon, orange, lime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the bowl of a standing mixer, using a knead hook, mix the yeast with the flour well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the butter and mix with until incorporated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the egg, the sugar, the vanilla extract and the baking soda. Keep kneading.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slowly add the water until the dough forms. Knead for a couple of minutes. The dough should be sticky so don’t add more flour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the dough with a damp towel and place in a warm surface (the stovetop should do fine).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the dough has doubled in size, transfer to a floured surface. Roll into a rectangular shape until the dough is about 1 cm thick.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut the dough in triangles. Shape the triangles into a crescent shape. To do this, put the triangle facing you upside down. Then roll it with your hands towards you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the medialunas in a baking sheet lined with parchment paper. Have each medialuna rest on the tips of the previous one (see pictures for reference), but leave some space between each other because they still need to rise one more time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let them rest in shape for about 10 more minutes or until risen. Paint them with an egg wash.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake in a pre-heated oven at 350°F for 20 minutes or until golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While they bake, make the syrup. In a small saucepan add the water, sugar and citrus slices. Don’t mix it and let it bring to a boil. When big bubbles form, turn off the heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the medialunas are out of the oven, brush the top with the syrup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="croissants" /><category term="medialunas" /><summary type="html">If you go to any bakery in Argentina (in Buenos Aires you’ll see one every two blocks), you’ll find lots of medialunas. They’re very similar to croissants in shape but the texture is slightly different.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/medialunas.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/medialunas.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Angel food cake</title><link href="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/angels-food-cake/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Angel food cake" /><published>2020-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/angels-food-cake</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/angels-food-cake/">&lt;p&gt;The first time I had Angel food cake was in the summer of 2019, after my husband Seb found a Betty Crocker Angel food cake box “very appealing” in the supermarket. It certainly looked very interesting: white and airy. I was super curious to find out what it tasted like. We had never heard of this type of cake back in Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/angel-food-cake-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Angel food cake served with strawberries&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only when we got home that I learned that I needed a special tin for this cake. Luckily, I had a non-stick bundt cake pan, and after some Googling, I confirmed it could replace the original Angel food cake pan just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the cake following the box instructions (including trying to figure out how to rest the cake upside down… 🤔). Tasting time comes… I loved the cake. Seb… not so much. He didn’t appreciate the almond flavoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months later, I decided to make this cake from scratch. I found a simple enough recipe on &lt;a href=&quot;https://tasty.co/recipe/angel-food-cake-in-a-springform-pan&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tasty&lt;/a&gt; and it turned out beautifully. Needless to say, I don’t use almond extract in the homemade version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/angel-food-cake-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Angel food cake before cutting&quot; width=&quot;558&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/4 cups egg whites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 cups sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350ºF.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sift the flour and 1/2 cup of the sugar in a medium bowl. Reserve.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measure the egg whites (I buy pasteurized egg whites, refer to the original Tasty recipe if you have whole eggs – you’ll need to use cream of tartar).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the bowl of a standing mixer, combine the egg whites, vanilla extract and salt. Beat in medium speed until soft peaks form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase the mixer speed and gradually incorporate the remaining 1 cup of sugar, 2 tablespoons at a time. Keep beaing until stiff peaks form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carfully sift the flour and sugar mixture into the egg whites mixture. Do this incrementally, 1/4 cup at a time. Fold softly with a spatula until there are no clumps left. Be careful not to overmix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer the batter into a non-greased non-stick bundt cake pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 45 minutes, or until the cake has risen and the top is golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While th cake bakes, prepare a wire rack and devise an “inverted cake holder”, as I like to call it. You need to invert the cake when it comes out of the oven, so find something you can use to keep it in place. I normally use the lid of my dutch oven, which has a flat handle (I rest the center of the inverted pan on the lid handle).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the cake from the oven and invert immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let it cool for at least 45 minutes before removing the cake from the pan. To remove, run a spatula (or something soft as to not ruin the non-stick surface of the pan) along the outer edge of the pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with berries!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="cake" /><category term="berries" /><summary type="html">The first time I had Angel food cake was in the summer of 2019, after my husband Seb found a Betty Crocker Angel food cake box “very appealing” in the supermarket. It certainly looked very interesting: white and airy. I was super curious to find out what it tasted like. We had never heard of this type of cake back in Argentina.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/angel-food-cake.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/angel-food-cake.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lemon meringue pie</title><link href="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/lemon-meringue-pie/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lemon meringue pie" /><published>2020-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/lemon-meringue-pie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/lemon-meringue-pie/">&lt;p&gt;My mom used to make lemon meringue pie (or simply &lt;em&gt;Lemon Pie&lt;/em&gt;, as we call it back home) all the time. My sister Mailen absolutely loves this pie, so it would always be her treat. I confess I wasn’t a fan of this dessert, I used to think it was too sour for my taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I got older, I started to appreciate this delicacy more and more. Nowadays, I could kill for a slice of lemon meringue pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried many, many recipes and not all attempts were successful. I tried different ways to make the filling, and in one of these attempts I came across condensed milk, and oh my. How have I lived so long without trying condensed milk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/lemon-meringue-pie-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lemon meringue pie fresh out of the oven&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my biggest problem always was the meringue. I tried French meringue first, because that’s how my mom does it, but it always ended up too fluffy for me and it lost its consistency if you didn’t eat it right away. I then moved on to Italian meringue and let me tell you: I hate this technique. I always messed it up – I either burnt the caramel (or it didn’t turn out syrup-y), or I burnt the egg whites. When it did come out right, the meringue over the pie would start to sweat after a day in the fridge. Not good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, until I tried making a Swiss meringue. The technique detailed here is not the textbook recipe, but it’s much simpler and most importantly, it works! The only gotcha is that it doesn’t last soft and creamy for too long, so the pie needs to be consumed in the first 1-3 days. Like that’s a problem…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/lemon-meringue-pie-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lemon meringue pie slice&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3a8_KIECzBI&quot;&gt;This recipe&lt;/a&gt; comes from a TV show from Argentina, called &lt;em&gt;Cocineros Argentinos&lt;/em&gt;. I watched it on YouTube. It’s long but really good. I couldn’t find the textual recipe in their website, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pie-dough&quot;&gt;Pie dough&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100g powdered sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;200g room-temperature butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;300g all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 lemon zest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;filling&quot;&gt;Filling&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;500ml milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;200g sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;60g cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 egg yolks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;200ml lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 lemon zest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;meringue&quot;&gt;Meringue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 egg whites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;240g sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix the butter with a spatula until soft. Add the powdered sugar slowly. Once incorporated, start mixing with an electric mixer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When the consistency becomes creamy and the colour lightens, add the egg and keep mixing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the flour and salt, and mix with a spatula until a firm dough forms. Do not overmix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Form a circle with the dough and cover with plastic wrap. Take to the fridge to rest for at least 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once chilled, roll the dough in a floured surface until circle covers pie dish, or an approximate height of 1 cm.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the pie dish and press against the side. Cut the excess dough. Tap base with a fork.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the dish and dough with aluminium foil and press. Add baking weights.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take to a pre-heated 350°F oven for about 15 minutes. After that time, remove the weights and foil, and cook for 5 more minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the dough bakes, start the filling. In a bowl beat the egg yolks with the sugar and cornstarch. Add the lemon juice and the zest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring the milk to a boil in a saucepan. Remove from heat and add about 1/4 of the milk into the yolks and sugar mixture. Mix to bring the temperature down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put the sauce pan back in the heat until it boils again. Once it does, slowly add the other mixture into the saucepan, mixing constantly. Keep beating until consistency thickens. Once it starts to boil, keep mixing for 1 more minute and then remove from the heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer the filling into a bowl and cover with plastic wrap. Ensure the wrap touches the filling to avoid it from developing a hard film on the top. Chill it in the fridge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once chilled, fill the cooked pie dough and leave it to rest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To make the meringue, add the egg whites and sugar into a microwave-safe bowl (or the bowl of a standing mixer is it’s glass). Mix to incorporate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook it on the microwave for 30 seconds. Take it out and mix it again with a whisk to prevent the egg whites from cooking. Do this process 5 times (1 time more than the amount of egg whites).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the last round is done, transfer to the bowl of a standing mixer (if you didn’t do it in there) and beat on medium-high speed until stiff peaks form, about 8 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decorate the pie with the meringue. You can use a piping bag or just put a layer of meringue on top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn the oven on, using the lowest broil setting. Place the pie in the oven and keep an eye on it. Broil only until the top darkens, about 1-2 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lemon" /><category term="meringue" /><category term="pie" /><summary type="html">My mom used to make lemon meringue pie (or simply Lemon Pie, as we call it back home) all the time. My sister Mailen absolutely loves this pie, so it would always be her treat. I confess I wasn’t a fan of this dessert, I used to think it was too sour for my taste.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/lemon-meringue-pie.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/lemon-meringue-pie.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hot cakes</title><link href="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/hot-cakes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hot cakes" /><published>2020-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/hot-cakes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/hot-cakes/">&lt;p&gt;Back in Argentina, we don’t really make pancakes or hot cakes as they’re commonly known in North America. Instead, we make crepes (which we call “panqueques”, as in &lt;em&gt;pancakes&lt;/em&gt;) with lots and lots of dulce de leche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom sent me this recipe to try not long ago and I was hooked because it’s so easy to make and they’re super delicious. They do not rise as much as regular pancakes, but they’re still amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hot-cakes-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hot cake with dulce de leche&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix all ingredients together until you get a thick and homogenous batter (I usually do this in a big measuring cup).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chill in fridge for at least 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush a pancake pan pre-heated in medium heat with butter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour about 1/4 cup batter from measuring cup in the pan, forming a circle of about 6cm in diameter. Do not move the pan!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flip when bubbles form in the surface, about after a minute and a half.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave for one more minute so the other side cooks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve hot! I like serving them with dulce de leche.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="pancakes" /><category term="dulce de leche" /><summary type="html">Back in Argentina, we don’t really make pancakes or hot cakes as they’re commonly known in North America. Instead, we make crepes (which we call “panqueques”, as in pancakes) with lots and lots of dulce de leche.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/hot-cakes.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/hot-cakes.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Carrot cake loaf</title><link href="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/carrot-cake-loaf/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Carrot cake loaf" /><published>2020-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/carrot-cake-loaf</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/carrot-cake-loaf/">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I had ordered a veggie box that came with a lot of carrots. I made soup and roasted carrots for dinner, and I still had a bunch left over. So I decided to experiment with a carrot cake loaf!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love making loafs, they’re so simple and versatile and they last me many breakfasts. They’re also very convenient to freeze since once it’s sliced, it doesn’t take up a lot of space. I always have a loaf in the freezer because it’s easy peasy to take out some slices, pop them in the microwave for a minute and have a breakfast (or a &lt;em&gt;merienda&lt;/em&gt;) ready in no time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I based this loaf in a recipe that I found on an healthy food Instagram account (I can’t remember which one), and as I was baking it, I adapted it to what I had in my pantry. It turned out great and my co-workers loved it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made it so late one weeknight that I completely forgot to take a picture of it, oopsies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 carrots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 banana&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup skim milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup brown sugar, plus extra to sprinkle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup steel cut oats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup whole wheat flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup all purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;walnuts to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;before-you-start-make-sure-to&quot;&gt;Before you start, make sure to…&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line a loaf tin with parchment paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 350°F.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;prepare-your-ingredients&quot;&gt;Prepare your ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop the walnuts to desired size (you can do this with a food processor).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peel and shred the carrots.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mash the banana with a fork.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Process the steel cut oats in a food processor until it’s similar to flour (not too fine).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix the dry ingredients (flours, spices, salt, baking powder and soda) and reserve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ready-get-set-bake&quot;&gt;Ready, get set, bake!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk the eggs in a bowl for a couple of minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix in the banana, sugar, milk, and vanilla extract and keep whisking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slowly integrate the dry ingredients while still whisking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At last, integrate the carrots and walnuts with a spatula.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour batter into the tin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle the top with a little of brown sugar to get a crispy crust.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 35 minutes or until sticking a knife to the middle of the loaf comes out dry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="carrot" /><category term="carrot cake" /><category term="loaf" /><summary type="html">Earlier this year, I had ordered a veggie box that came with a lot of carrots. I made soup and roasted carrots for dinner, and I still had a bunch left over. So I decided to experiment with a carrot cake loaf!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dulce de leche ice cream</title><link href="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/dulce-de-leche-ice-cream/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dulce de leche ice cream" /><published>2019-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/dulce-de-leche-ice-cream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/dulce-de-leche-ice-cream/">&lt;p&gt;In case it wasn’t clear before: dulce de leche is my favourite food. And one of the things I miss most from Argentina is good quality ice cream. In Buenos Aires, you can order ice cream to be delivered to your door pretty much 24/7, all year round. You order it by the kilogram. We love our ice cream. And the best flavour in my opinion is – you guessed it – dulce de leche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dulce-de-leche-ice-cream-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dulce de leche ice cream served with strawberries&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find any ice cream flavour that you can imagine. Anything with dulce de leche in it will be in my order. I go back and forth, but one of my all-time favourites is &lt;em&gt;super dulce de leche granizado&lt;/em&gt;, which basically is a dulce de leche cream, with chocolate chips and natural dulce de leche swirls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making ice cream at home is not an easy feat. You typically need the fancy ice cream machines to get decent ice cream. I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paulinacocina.net/helado-de-dulce-de-leche-casero/8679&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this recipe by Paulina Cocina&lt;/a&gt; (she’s a great home cook) and it seemed too simple to be true. I set out to try it and the results are really good. It’s nothing like you’d find in a Buenos Aires &lt;em&gt;heladería&lt;/em&gt;, but it’s pretty decent. The only reason why I don’t make this every weekend is that it takes over a day to get it done. I usually need to start making it very early on a Saturday to enjoy it on Sunday. But it’s worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dulce-de-leche-ice-cream-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dulce de leche ice cream in the making&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;500 g dulce de leche&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;250 ml heavy cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;250 ml milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chocolate chips (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;more dulce de leche for the swirls (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a standing mixer, beat the dulce de leche with the heavy cream until smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add milk and beat a little longer, until well combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the bowl with plastic wrap and place in the freezer for 2 to 3 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After 2-3 hours, remove bowl from freezer and beat again for a bit, until it creamy. Take back to the freezer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat this process a few times, until the consistency is ice-cream-like.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before putting in the freezer for the last time, add chocolate chips and spoonfuls of dulce de leche. Mix carefully with a spatula to integrate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with an ice cream scoop. I like serving it with strawberries, more dulce de leche and wafers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="dulce de leche" /><category term="ice cream" /><category term="chocolate chips" /><summary type="html">In case it wasn’t clear before: dulce de leche is my favourite food. And one of the things I miss most from Argentina is good quality ice cream. In Buenos Aires, you can order ice cream to be delivered to your door pretty much 24/7, all year round. You order it by the kilogram. We love our ice cream. And the best flavour in my opinion is – you guessed it – dulce de leche.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/dulce-de-leche-ice-cream.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/dulce-de-leche-ice-cream.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple pie</title><link href="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/apple-pie/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple pie" /><published>2019-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/apple-pie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/apple-pie/">&lt;p&gt;If I had to choose one favourite sweet treat, it’d probably be apple pie. My mom used to make it for me all the time when I was a kid, and I confess I usually eat the pie all by myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Argentina, you can find ready-made pie dough in every supermarket. A very well known comfort food are “tartas” which are basically two (or sometimes one) disc of dough filled with whatever you can imagine. These discs of dough are very thin, flaky and delicious. &lt;em&gt;Tartas&lt;/em&gt; tend to be savoury, but the same dough can be used for sweet pies, like the apple pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/apple-pie-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Freshly baked apple pie&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I came here, I couldn’t find this type of dough anywhere. I found some things that are only vaguely related, like puff pastry, philo pastry and pie dough (which is way thicker and heavy). I tried to make &lt;em&gt;tartas&lt;/em&gt; with all of these pastries/doughs to no avail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when it came to make apple pie (I get special cravings in the fall, who doesn’t?), I made the dough from scratch. And let me tell you it’s even better than using &lt;em&gt;tarta&lt;/em&gt; dough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried many recipes, some using butter and some using shortening (I think I even tried lard). But the best one yet is this one from Binging with Babish. I originally tried the one in the book (which is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bingingwithbabish.com/recipes/2017/8/22/applepie&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;posted here&lt;/a&gt;), but Babish &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i7648rZpdck&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;posted an improved version&lt;/a&gt; of this recipe in his YouTube channel last year and it’s much better. I modified the filling a bit to my tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I promised by co-workers many times to bring apple pie to the office but I never did because they never lasted that long!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/apple-pie-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A slice of apple pie&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pie-dough&quot;&gt;Pie dough&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/4 cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;225 grams of butter, frozen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iced water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;filling&quot;&gt;Filling&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 large Granny Smith apples (approximately 1.2kg)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;zest of 1/2 lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;decoration&quot;&gt;Decoration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a bowl, combine flour and salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a hand-held grater, grate the frozen butter on top of the bowl, until all butter is grated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slowly mixing with a spatula, add iced water, one tablespoon at a time, to the mixture until the dough starts to hold together. The amount of water depends on a lot of factors, so do this slowly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer the dough to a clean, floured surface and start kneading gently.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Form a disc with the dough and wrap it in plastic wrap. Place it in the fridge for at least 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the dough rest, peel the apples. Remove the core and cut them in approximately 2cm slices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer the apple slices to a large bowl and incorporate the sugar, flour, lemon juice, lemon zest and spices. Mix it well and let rest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After 30 minutes, take the dough out of the fridge and divide it in two equal parts. Put one of them back in the fridge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a floured surface, roll the dough out to a circle at least 5 cm wider than the pie plate. Using the rolling pin, carefully transfer the disc over the pie plate. Remove excess dough hanging from the sides.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place it back in the fridge while you roll out the rest of the dough into a circle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove pie plate from the fridge and fill with the apple filling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover with the second dough disc. Press the borders so the pie is tightly sealed. Cut triangles at the top (see picture) so steam can escape.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush the top with an egg wash and sprinkle with sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place pie in a 425°F oven for 35-50 minutes or until the dough looks golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rest until completely cool before serving (at least 2 hours).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="apple" /><category term="pie" /><summary type="html">If I had to choose one favourite sweet treat, it’d probably be apple pie. My mom used to make it for me all the time when I was a kid, and I confess I usually eat the pie all by myself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/apple-pie.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/apple-pie.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Brownies</title><link href="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/brownies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brownies" /><published>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/brownies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/brownies/">&lt;p&gt;Brownies are so easy to make, and they always turn out delicious. Everyone loves brownies, even people who don’t love chocolate, like me! You can make them plain, or add walnuts for a crunchier result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/brownies-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Brownie pan straight out of the oven&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;125 g butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;150 g dark chocolate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 cup sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup chopped walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare a square or rectangular pan (makes cutting easier). Grease and line the pan with parchment paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dice butter and chop chocolate (in case you’re not using chips). Place both in a glass bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the bowl over a saucepan with boiling water (water should not reach the top). This will act as a double boiler. Leave the bowl there until butter and chocolate melt, without mixing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In another bowl, whisk the eggs with the sugar and the vanilla extract.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the chocolate and butter mixture has melted and cooled down, slowly incorporate the egg and sugar mixture into it while beating.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sift the flour over the batter. Incorporate it slowly with a spatula. Do not overmix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the chopped walnuts (or any other nut), and mix briefly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the batter in the pan and take to a pre-heated, 350°F oven. Bake for 20 minutes or until batter is set when pan you shake the pan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="brownies" /><category term="chocolate" /><summary type="html">Brownies are so easy to make, and they always turn out delicious. Everyone loves brownies, even people who don’t love chocolate, like me! You can make them plain, or add walnuts for a crunchier result.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/brownies.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/brownies.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cheesecake</title><link href="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/cheesecake/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cheesecake" /><published>2018-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/cheesecake</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://bakery.ar/recipes/sweet/cheesecake/">&lt;p&gt;What’s not to love about cheesecake? It’s delicious and it’s also relatively simple to make. Win-win! I love making this cheesecake for birthdays (especially my own), and it’s always super successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made my first cheesecake in Canada using the Philadelphia cream cheese &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kraftwhatscooking.ca/recipe/classic-philadelphia-cheesecake-recipe-philadelphia-brick-cream-cheese-82700&quot;&gt;original cheesecake recipe&lt;/a&gt; and I have since adapted (and let me say, &lt;em&gt;perfectioned&lt;/em&gt;) it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cheesecake-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberry cheesecake&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to make it from scratch with Graham cracker crumbs (like the big one on the picture), and I still do sometimes. But I found that using the ready-made Graham pie crust works better and it’s quicker. 💫&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cheesecake-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Slice of cheesecake&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 pkg. (250 g each) Philadelphia Brick Cream Cheese, softened&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2/3 cup sugar (1/2 cup for filling, the rest for the jam)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp. vanilla&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ready-to-use graham cracker crumb crust (9-inch)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pint raspberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-heat oven to 325°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beat cream cheese, sugar and vanilla in the bowl of a standing mixer until blended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the eggs and beat just until blended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour into crust. Bake for 40 minutes or until centre is almost set.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from the oven and let it cool. Refrigerate 3 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To make the jam, mix 2/3 of the raspberries with the sugar in a medium-sized saucepan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring the saucepan into the stovetop and cook in low heat for 15 minutes or until jam has no lumps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from the heat and let it cool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour on top of the chilled cheesecake. Decorate with the remaining raspberries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="berries" /><category term="raspberries" /><category term="cheese" /><category term="cheesecake" /><category term="cake" /><summary type="html">What’s not to love about cheesecake? It’s delicious and it’s also relatively simple to make. Win-win! I love making this cheesecake for birthdays (especially my own), and it’s always super successful.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/cheesecake.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://bakery.ar/featured/cheesecake.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>